<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Standards Track on Handshake Improvement Proposals</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/category/standards-track/</link><description>Recent content in Standards Track on Handshake Improvement Proposals</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/category/standards-track/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stateless DANE clients</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0017/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0017/</guid><description>Abstract This document proposes a standard for a new form of light clients that use extremely minimal resources suitable for embedding in web browser applications, especially on mobile devices. Clients only store tiny 32-byte Merkle tree roots and can use them to verify TLS trustlessly for any Handshake site completely off-chain, without doing any extra network lookups compared to traditional sites and without maintaining a stateful connection to a p2p network.</description></item><item><title>Interactive Atomic Name Swaps</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0004/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0004/</guid><description>Abstract We define a protocol by which two Handshake users can agree on a price for a HNS domain name, and swap the name itself for payment in HNS using a single transaction. The buyer and seller must be able to interact before and during the protocol, and the final transaction is signed by both parties.
Motivation HNS users need a decentralized, platform-less way to sell the domain names they&amp;rsquo;ve acquired form on-chain auctions.</description></item><item><title>Non-Interactive Name Atomic Swaps</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0001/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0001/</guid><description>Abstract This document proposes a standard way for Handshake names to be traded on a secondary market without the need of a trusted third party to act as an escrow.
Motivation A healthy secondary market for Handshake names will bring more activity to the Handshake economy. Without a solution for a decentralized secondary market, it is likely that most names will end up being managed on a custodial platform where there is liquidity for names.</description></item></channel></rss>