<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Informational on Handshake Improvement Proposals</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/category/informational/</link><description>Recent content in Informational on Handshake Improvement Proposals</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/category/informational/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DANE for Decentralized Naming Systems (dDANE)</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0007/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0007/</guid><description>Abstract ICANN-rooted DNS is not the only internet naming system available to users, but it is the only naming system in which certificate authorities issue SSL certificates. Since SSL certificates are the mechanism behind HTTPS, browsing securely to websites outside the ICANN-rooted DNS is difficult and out of scope for the majority of users.
DANE is a protocol that uses DNSSEC to authenticate SSL certificates as presented by a web server and could be used to bypass certificate authorities, assuming the naming system is trusted or cryptographically secure.</description></item><item><title>Trustless Live Auctions for Handshake</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0006/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0006/</guid><description>Abstract We propose an ascending-price auction system for HNS domain names without trust or third-party custody. A name owner initiates an auction by locking their TLD with a verifiable script. Bidders place bids by partially-signing TRANSFER transactions, and the name owner eventually picks the highest bid and atomically swaps the name ownership for the payment. The protocol requires more interactivity and centralization than the current Shakedex-style HIP-0001 auction format, but with some compelling trade-offs.</description></item><item><title>Name data standard for alternative namespace resolution</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0005/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0005/</guid><description>Abstract This HIP describes how to set the data for a Handshake name so that it can resolved via an external namespace or alternative consensus system. Resolution must be performed by an extension to a Handshake resolver which may not be included by default in full or light clients.
Motivation There may be various reasons to resolve a name on an alternative namespace other than a domain name or an name server hosted on an IP address.</description></item><item><title>Well Known directory for wallets address</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0002/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0002/</guid><description>Abstract This HIP describes how to publish a wallet address in a domain.
Motivation Wallet address are not human friendly. Sending an address normally involves &amp;ldquo;copy &amp;amp; paste&amp;rdquo; and is nearly impossible to do via voice channels.
Since Handshake is all about owning domains, we could use them as aliases to our wallet addresses.
Protocol The basics of this protocol consists of serving the address in an HTTPS request to the .</description></item><item><title>HIP Template</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0000/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0000/</guid><description>Abstract This is a section for an abstract.
Motivation This is a section for a motivation.
Body This is a section for a body. The title of the section should be changed and the section can be split into multiple sections and subsections.
References This is a section for references such as links to other documents (BIP or HIP) or to reference implementations.</description></item></channel></rss>