<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Standards on Handshake Improvement Proposals</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/category/standards/</link><description>Recent content in Standards on Handshake Improvement Proposals</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/category/standards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Extend reserve name claim period with hard fork</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0014/</guid><description>Tweet-sized abstract Important reserved names (about 1,000) stay reserved for 4 additional years, a total of 8. The rest of the reserved names (about 89,000) become available for auctions after 4 years (no change) See the section &amp;ldquo;Example opinions&amp;rdquo; for better understanding.
Abstract Handshake was launched with a set of reserved names that can be claimed by their current legacy DNS owners using DNSSEC proofs. The claimPeriod was originally set to exactly four years (4 * 365 * 144 = 210,240 blocks) after which any of the reserved names could be OPEN for an auction and acquired by the usual bidding process.</description></item><item><title>The Meta Account Key</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0011/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0011/</guid><description>Abstract There are some wallet operations that do not require addresses for receiving HNS on chain. However, BIP32 recoverability is still desired for metadata that may be involved in these operations. For these operations, we define a constant account index of 0xffffffff as &amp;ldquo;The Meta Account&amp;rdquo;. Derivation paths from this account key should be specified in this document to track future standard uses for The Meta Account Key.
Motivation Hardware Wallets Hardware wallets like Ledger Nano S and Nano X support multiple coin types.</description></item><item><title>Standard Recoverable Script Addresses</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0009/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0009/</guid><description>Abstract We propose a method for generating application-specific scripts and scripthash addresses by deriving key pairs from specific BIP44 branches.
Motivation Secondary market protocols, like Shakedex (see HIP-1), currently generate a new private key for each script address, which makes recovery possible only as long as the user has backed up each individual key they generate. By deterministically deriving script addresses using a standard BIP44 wallet seed, we can recover the user&amp;rsquo;s auction listing and pending fills by importing the seed, re-generating the script addresses and re-scanning the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Recoverable Bid Values</title><link>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0008/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hsd-dev.org/HIPs/proposals/0008/</guid><description>Abstract We propose a method for embedding encrypted bid values on the blockchain using nulldata outputs. Values are encrypted using a combination of a user&amp;rsquo;s private key and other data recoverable from the blockchain.
Motivation The Handshake reference implementation (hsd) includes a wallet (hsw) that mostly conforms to BIP44. The goal of BIP44 is to allow a recovery process whereby a user could restore the complete state of their wallet using only their wallet&amp;rsquo;s master private key (usually encoded by a BIP39 seed phrase) and all the public data available on the blockchain.</description></item></channel></rss>